<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-boston-subway</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024441/1897-03-04/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Escaping Gas in Boston Subway Works Great Havoc.
  HALF A HUNDRED INJURED
  Passing Electric Car Wrecked and Adjoining Buildings Badly Damaged Partial List of Dead and Disabled Accident Occurred at Tremont and Boylston Streets.
  Boston, March 4. An explosion has just occurred in the subway excavation at the corner of Tremont and Boylston streets.
  Three electric cars that were passing at the time were wrecked and one of them was burned. Several buildings in the vicinity were more or less damaged.
  The explosion was caused by escaping gas.
  Among the buildings damaged are the Hotel Pelham, the Knickerbocker and Head buildings and the Masonic Temple. Window glass in buildings within 200 feet of the scene of the explosion were shattered.
  At least twelve persons were killed. Four bodies have been removed to undertaking rooms. Forty-two persons are at the Emergency Hospital.
  Among the dead are: Rev. W. A. Slack, professor at Tufts College. G. D. Bigelow, conductor. Unknown man and woman.
  The injured include James Reardon, John J. O'Connor, Thomas F. Ford, Mrs. J. R. Wilson, Nellie Jackson, Lucy Dolan, F. W. Teeling, and Mrs. F. A. Peck.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1897-09-19/ed-1/seq-32/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  UNDERGROUND TRAVEL.
  THE BOSTON SUBWAY PARTLY COMPLETED AND IN OPERATION.
  The subway for streetcars in Boston, a part of which has just been opened for service, is an enterprise of more than local interest. The necessity for some relief to the crowded thoroughfares 
  above it can best be appreciated by Bostonians; but the Modern Athens is by no means the only city in this country which is beset with problems of the same character.
  Those who are familiar with "the lay of the land" in Boston remember that Tremont Street runs in a generally north-and-south direction and forms the eastern boundary of the Common. 
  It is intersected by Boylston Street, which constitutes the southern boundary of that historic park. On the Boylston and Tremont Street edges of the Common there is a broad promenade, known as the Mall. 
  The main part of the subway, which is wide enough to accommodate four tracks, passes under the Tremont Street Mall, and after passing under Park Street, which lies along the northern side of the Common, 
  extends (or will extend, when completed) to Scollay Square, thence eastward to Adams Square, and finally northward again to Haymarket Square. This terminus is close to the great union railway station at the North End.
  From the corner of Tremont and Boylston Streets, there are two extensions wide enough for only a double track. One runs westward under Boylston Street Mall for about 950 feet, 
  and then ascends an incline through an open cut for 450 feet. The terminal station for this branch is situated in the Public Gardens. The other branch reaches away to the southward, 
  and, on nearing the junction of Shawmut Avenue and Tremont Street, forks. A separate two-track incline leads up into each of those streets.
  Including the inclines, the subway has a total length of about a mile and a half, and will contain about five miles of track. At present, the branches from the corner of Boylston and Tremont Streets, 
  and the main line up to Park Street, are in operation. A great deal of work has already been done on the northern portion of the route, and it is hoped that everything will be finished within the next eight months. 
  Ground was broken for the subway in April 1895, twenty-nine months ago. ...
  At present, the only stations in use underground are at the corner of Boylston and Tremont Streets and at Park Street. When the subway is completed, however, there will be other stations at Scollay Square, 
  Adams Square, and Haymarket Square.
  The capacity of the subway is ninety cars per minute. Inasmuch as the facilities thus afforded are supplementary to those already afforded on Tremont Street, and are not a substitute for the latter, 
  a distinct increase in the number of passengers, as well as freedom from blockades, has been secured.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn95079490/1897-10-23/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  THE BOSTON SUBWAY
  SATISFACTORY SOLUTION OF THE STREET CAR PROBLEM
  Congestion of traffic in the busy streets of the hub relieved by underground trolley lines—tunnels that are light, clean, and attractive.
  It is now possible to cross Tremont street, Boston, at any point opposite the Common and at any time of day without loss of life or limb. The new subway has brought about the change.
  It is an old tradition that the fathers of Boston, when they laid out the city, let the streets follow the winding cow paths. At any rate, the streets as they exist today are very crooked and most of them are very narrow. 
  This was all right in Revolutionary times, but when the city grew miles beyond the Common and spread itself out to the south and west; when business centered itself along the lower ends of Washington and Tremont streets, 
  and when dozens of street car tracks usurped the narrow roadways, then the Bostonians wished their ancestors had not stuck so closely to the cow paths.
  Probably no other city on the continent was ever so badly afflicted with a congestion of traffic as the Hub has been for many years. Some of the most important streetcar lines skirt the south and east corners of 
  the Common on Boylston and Tremont streets. When the change was made from horse-power to trolley, matters grew worse. Then the poles and the tangle of overhead wires made that historic breathing spot look like a piece of dingy, 
  green billiard cloth which had become frayed and tattered around the edges. So after much wrangling in the legislature and courts it was decided to build the subway and put the trolley cars underground.
  A large portion of the work has already been accomplished and Boston is delighted with the result.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1897-12-15/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  BOSTON'S UNUSED SUBWAY
  UNDERGROUND TRANSIT A FAILURE
  Before any further attempt is made to commit this city to the building of the proposed underground system of rapid transit, it would be well for everyone interested to learn something of the experience which Boston is now having 
  with its subway. Boston's subway is New York's proposed underground railroad in miniature, except that it was constructed for the use of the trolley car lines instead of being equipped with cars, motors, and power of its own.
  The Boston subway is short. That part now in use is less than a mile in length, and the parts under construction or proposed would add only about another mile to the tunnel net. There is, perhaps, no finer specimen of passenger 
  tunnel work anywhere in the world, and it is doubtful if any more perfect tunnel could be constructed.
  The subway was built to relieve the congestion of traffic on the streets. Yet, three months' experience has shown that the Boston subway is not popular, that people will not go into it except when they have to, and that the subway 
  is a failure, save so far as it was a necessity to relieve the congestion of traffic on the street.
  NEED OF THE SUBWAY
  Boston's subway was designed to meet a pressing need. Ten years ago, the West End Street Railway Company began to transform the horse car lines into electric trolley lines. The added cars required for the new service fairly filled 
  the streets of the little central city, where they were all concentrated. To relieve this congestion, the Boston Transit Commission was appointed to devise a suitable solution.
  OPERATIVE CONTRACT
  The city of Boston pays for the subway and leases it to the West End Street Railway Company for twenty years, at an annual rental. The subway was opened for use in sections starting on Sept. 1, and a second section opened on Sept. 30. 
  The subway lies under Tremont street, with stations built commodiously underground, approached by wide, easy stairways.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016413/1901-07-24/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Since the Boston subway was completed, a large part of the population spends its time underground, riding back and forth through the tunnel and exclaiming: 'We did it!'
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1903-06-21/ed-1/seq-42/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Within three years the crooks and turnings of Boston's most honored highways and byways will be nothing more than a memory of the past... Slowly and surely the ancient thoroughfares are being widened, straightened, 
  and bent into the rulerlike lines of crosscut New York, Philadelphia, and Chicago.
  Along State-st., beneath the spot where the Boston Massacre occurred, and beneath the historic old State House, a tunnel is eating its way from under the harbor to Scollay Square to connect with the present subway by means of 
  flights of stairs and elevators, and thence outside to the busy world. The old State House itself is to be transformed into a tunnel station connecting with a subway line.
  The Park-st. station of the present subway handles 27,000,000 passengers a year in the course of its trolley traffic, but the number of passengers who will pass through the old State House station will far exceed this number.
  Down Washington-st., to connect with the tunnel and present subway, will be another subway, this a double one for elevated trains after they leave the surface at the Broadway extension. It will pass beneath the Old South Church, 
  the Old Corner Bookstore, and other well-known landmarks.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020274/1904-05-08/ed-1/seq-57/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085947/1904-10-27/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87060004/1905-01-19/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  ANOTHER BOSTON SUBWAY East Boston Tunnel Just Opens, Diving Under Harbor
  Boston, the pioneer city of America in subway construction, now boasts a subway said to be the greatest single boring yet completed under the center of a river or harbor. It is the East Boston tunnel, extending from the 
  city proper under the harbor to Maverick Square, East Boston. It is the second subway to be opened in Boston, was begun in 1900, has cost $3,000,000, and has just been turned over to the Boston Elevated Railway company 
  for operation. It is about one and two-fifths miles in length and has an exterior diameter of nearly thirty feet, though the thickness of the walls brings its interior diameter down to about twenty-four feet.
  The East Boston tunnel reaches a depth of more than ninety feet below the waters of Boston harbor, through a blue clay sediment. It is for the use of regular trolley cars, which come to the surface at the suburban end of 
  the passage and continue their journeys over the street tracks. Eventually, the tube will be connected directly with the present subway in Boston's congested district.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84023296/1906-06-09/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  FIRE IN SUBWAY.
  Lives Imperilled in Boston's Underground Railway.
  Terrific Explosions Caused by Short Circuiting of Heavily Charged Electric Wires — Hundreds of Men and Women Thrown Into Panic — Three Persons Injured.
  Boston — A dull, low roar, like the blast of a charge of dynamite under tons of granite, and clouds of black, sickening smoke belching forth, threw hundreds of men and women into a panic and paralyzed traffic in the 
  subway at the Boylston Street station at 5:30 o'clock, Wednesday afternoon.
  No one knew the trouble. Elevated road employees and officials were alike confused, and fearful of what might come next, as the smoke rapidly filled the stations at Boylston and Park Streets, and passengers were rushed 
  from the cars to the surface.
  Trainmen and station police attempted to call the fire department and found the telephones so charged with electricity as to be useless.
  Many of the women reaching the subway by the Boylston Street cars were overcome by the smoke, fainted, and had to be dragged to the surface. Several became hysterical and were controlled with much difficulty, the danger being 
  constant of someone falling from the platforms, overcome by the smoke, and becoming electrocuted upon the deadly third rail.
  Trainmaster Benjamin was the first official to reach the Boylston Street station and to bring some sort of order out of the chaos. Entering the subway along the line of the northbound cars, he made his way some 100 feet to the 
  south of the station and found the cause of the trouble.
  The feed cables for the third rail, running between the rails and enclosed in four-inch wooden box conduits, were found grounded and throwing off flashes of electricity, which illuminated the subway for many hundreds of feet. 
  The electricity had jumped to other cables running parallel, and even charged the walls of the subway. Ten powerful cables felt the influence of the cross and were crackling and throwing off flames and flashes of light, threatening death to any who came near.
  The wooden box conduit, black and greasy and very inflammable, was burning rapidly. A northbound train which had passed over the spot got on fire and was pulled back to Pleasant Street, blazing fiercely underneath. The terrified passengers were hurried off at 
  Pleasant Street, and the fire beneath the train was extinguished by road employees before serious damage was done.
  Three persons were hurt, and all of them were on the surface. The accidents which caused their injuries were the direct result of the trouble in the subway. The injured were all near the Pleasant Street entrance to the subway and were hurt by the explosions 
  in three manholes at that point.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87078082/1910-12-07/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  JOHN F. DONOHUE A SUICIDE. Thomas Lawson's Confidential Man Dies In Subway. Boston, Dec. 1. John F. Donohue, many years the confidential man of J. Edward Addicks and of Thomas W. Lawson, committed suicide by throwing himself before a fast-moving train in the subway. 
  Death was instantaneous. For about fifteen minutes Mr. Donohue had been pacing the station platform, walking to the edge and looking down at the rails and peering up and down the track. Just before a northbound train drew up Mr. Donohue dropped a light cane he had 
  been carrying and jumped into the train pit. His family furnished no explanation for the act. Friends say he had been suffering from stomach trouble about a year. He was sixty years old and a native of Ireland and for a time was engaged in shoe manufacturing in Lynn, Mass.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1912-06-07/ed-1/seq-30/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Boston, June 7. By noon today the surface, elevated, and subway car system of Boston and suburbs was utterly disorganized. A strike of the union employees of the Boston Elevated, which controls the surface and subway lines, was called at 4:15 o'clock this morning after a 
  stormy three-hour session at union headquarters. The elevated officials laughed at the strike. When the union was formed only a few weeks ago the elevated set about a counter organization, a 'protective' association they called it.
  This morning the officials of the company claimed they had 2,000 men in this protective association who would continue to work, and that they had 1,500 strike-breakers already imported from New York and Philadelphia.
  There was a good deal of rioting after the strike was called. Cars were stoned, trolleys disconnected, motormen and conductors who refused to recognize the strike order roughly handled, sleepers were put on the tracks, and cautious Bostonians walked to work this morning.
  Because the guards at the Park street terminal of the Cambridge subway reported to the union the escalators were stopped and passengers had to climb three flights of stairs to the street.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn97067598/1919-07-21/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Traffic Resumed On Boston Subway, Elevated And Surface Lines" "BOSTON, July 21 Traffic on the surface, subway, and elevated lines of Greater Boston was resumed today after an interruption of four days caused by the strike of Carmen who demanded an eight-hour day and an 
  increase in wages. They were granted an eight-hour day and an increase in wages, the maximum being 62 1/2 cents an hour.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1919-08-17/ed-1/seq-63/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  We may revile the New York subway, we may grumble at every step as we 'follow the green arrow' along the circuitous path that leads from the Grand Central Station to Times Square, but, let me tell you, this is a 'strait and narrow path' compared with the complicated maze 
  of the Boston so-called 'rapid transit' system. Everybody gets lost in the Boston subway, even the oldest inhabitant, and they expect to get lost and calculate their time for reaching their destination accordingly.
  'How do you ever know where to go?' I asked my mother, who has a pretty good bump of location.
  'I don't know,' she replied. 'Nobody knows. One just keeps on trying until one finds the right train.'
  A visit to the Park Street Station of this underground maze during rush hours—if there can be said to be such a time in Boston—is much more amusing than going to the circus. The would-be travelers meander slowly down the steps of the barest, coldest, 
  most cheerless dungeon that civilized man ever paid ten cents to enter. They are laden with parcels, including—we are forced to admit it—the much ridiculed Boston bag. In my day, these were made of cloth with leather ends and were used principally by 
  the women of the community. Now they are made entirely of leather and are equally popular with both men and women.
  Slowly the travelers descend the steps, and there is a fixed, glassy look in their eyes. They stumble and jostle one another, now and then a parcel is dropped, and this causes a momentary pause in the descending stream, but the eyes of the throng are never raised or lowered, 
  no one ever glances to the right or left, nothing short of an earthquake would cause the multitude to remove its eyes from the indicator, which by means of illuminated figures tells at which white post each car will stop.
  A figure 4 flashes forth. The slow procession becomes a mad rush for post No. 4. Children squeal and perform a sort of Maypole dance around the whitewashed pillars; sedate elderly women pick up their skirts and hurl themselves into the throng; the Boston bags vibrate with the excitement.
  A car approaches, and they surge on board. The only calm person in the lot is the conductor. The Boston conductor is always calm, always polite; he never loses his poise or his temper nor fails to answer the most asinine question in a most respectful manner.
  'Be very careful, madam,' he says, 'the step is unusually high; take your time, the car will wait.' Quite different from the 'Step lively!' of his New York brother, which is usually accompanied with a push on the back.
  Just as the car, now filled to the last inch of standing room, is about to start, the conductor addresses the multitude: 'This car goes to Jamaica Plain,' he says.
  There is a great to-do. The tide turns. There is a general exodus, a grand rush for the door, a buzz of conversation. The wrong car stopped at post No. 4. The conductor, who was absolutely blameless in the matter, apologizes most abjectly for the mistake.
  The crowd, back once more on the cold concrete floor of the dungeon, fixes its eyes on the indicator with the same long-suffering, patient stare. It hasn't long to wait. Another car comes into view around the curve—another car? No, on second glance, it is a 
  train of cars. It stops at post No. 4, and the Maypole dance is repeated, and this time there is no mistake. But never, never in all my life have I seen anything like this train of cars.
  Here is a bright and shining example of New England thrift, for who but a New Englander, I ask you, would ever have conceived the idea of taking two old cars and joining them in the middle by means of a bit of another car so that they look exactly like two rooms 
  and a bath on wheels? Yet they answer the purpose very well. They have one 'prepayment' car, which, if you please, is Bostonesque for 'pay-as-you-enter.'
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90005351/1921-12-23/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  EXPLOSION SCARE IN BOSTON SUBWAY
  BOSTON, Dec. 23—Traffic was paralyzed for two hours and thousands of commuters and Christmas shoppers frightened in underground trains when a main power cable in the Cambridge subway grounded and exploded, thus shutting off the current. Confusion broke loose in 
  the vicinity between Chauncey street and the South Station when volumes of black smoke poured through the tube and permeated to adjoining subway systems. The officials of the road declare that there were no injuries resulting from the accident.
  </text>
      </result>

# Ten additional documents from Chronicling America
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1912-06-07/ed-1/seq-30/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  BOSTON'S SUBWAY, SURFACE AND ELEVATED LINES PRACTICALLY TIED UP BY STRIKE
  Boston, June 7. By noon today the surface, elevated, and subway car system of Boston and suburbs was utterly disorganized. A strike of the union employees of the Boston Elevated, which controls the surface and subway lines, 
  was called at 4:15 o'clock this morning after a stormy three-hour session at union headquarters.
  There was a good deal of rioting after the strike was called. Cars were stoned, trolleys disconnected, motormen and conductors who refused to recognize the strike order were roughly handled, sleepers were put on the tracks, 
  and cautious Bostonians walked to work this morning.
  As the forenoon wore on, motormen after motormen, and conductor after conductor left their packed cars standing in the street and went to union headquarters to report.
  Even where they did not leave the cars, there was always someone to disconnect the trolley wires. Then the motormen and conductors would refuse to get off to fix it, and the police would have to do it.
  Because the guards at the Park Street terminal of the Cambridge subway reported to the union, the escalators were stopped, and passengers had to climb three flights of stairs to the street.
  Police Commissioner O'Meara ordered all the reserves on duty at the subway and elevated stations and car barns this forenoon.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83007465/1906-08-11/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Boston's Subway cars honeycomb the city. Surface and elevated cars are also in evidence.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92073954/1921-12-23/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  CONFUSION IN BOSTON SUBWAY
  Boston, Dec. 23.—Traffic was stopped for two hours and thousands of Christmas shoppers and commuters were trapped in the underground tubes when the main power cable in the Cambridge subway grounded and exploded. 
  When smoke began to enter the tubes the passengers on the cars came near being panic stricken. The casualties and the damage was slight.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1912-03-23/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Boston's Subway Opened.
  BOSTON, Mass., March 23.—The new subway system for the handling of the heavy passenger traffic between Boston and Cambridge, was formally opened today. The tunnel, which is three and a quarter miles in length, 
  starts at the Park Street station of the old subway, and passes under Boston Common, Beacon Hill, and Charles river to Harvard square in Cambridge.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86069313/1905-04-28/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn91068499/1899-06-16/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020438/1915-12-04/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1902-12-09/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Boston's Subway Opened.
  BOSTON, Mass., March 23.—The new subway system for the handling of the heavy passenger traffic between Boston and Cambridge, was formally opened to-day. The tunnel, which is three and a quarter miles in length, 
  starts at the Park Street station of the old subway, and passes under Boston Common, Beacon Hill, and Charles river to Harvard square in Cambridge.
  The engineers of the Interborough Rapid Transit Company, otherwise known as the subway, are struggling with the important problem of doing away with the noise in the tunnel incident to the rapid operation of its trains, 
  which, if all plans work out well, will be carrying passengers in about one year. The grinding, ear-splitting noises in the Boston subway and the thunderous ringing of the Fourth ave. cars as they pass under the surface 
  between Thirty-fourth and Forty-second sts. are object lessons which the builders of the new tunnel system are trying to profit by. A prominent official of the Interborough company said yesterday: "We can't get rid of all 
  the noise, although we would like to. Steel wheels running on steel rails at a high rate of speed will make a lot of noise, and this is accentuated when the road is in a tunnel and the ballast under the rails is rigid, 
  as our ballasting is likely to be. Still, we are in hope of deadening the noise to such an extent that it will not be disagreeably noticeable. Our engineers are devoting a great deal of time to mastering the problem, 
  and we hope they will be able to thrash out something satisfactory."
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn96090259/1906-09-14/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84020358/1899-10-20/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Of course, I hunted out the entrance to the subway among the first things. Some three years ago the Boston subway commissioners kindly sent to me a copy of their report, in which, illustrated by excellent photographs, 
  were to be seen certain stations and parts of the roadway of this Budapest subway contrasted and compared with that then nearing completion in our own city. In anticipation of this ride through the subway here let me say 
  that coming through London I resolved to take a ride upon its new electric system, which is now in operation between the Mansion House (city) and Waterloo station. I do not think even with the greatest stretch of words 
  that the English hole in the ground can be called a subway. It is a deep and would be a dark tunnel were it not for the electric lights throughout the passage. One is attracted by a sign opposite the Mansion House with the legend, 
  'Trains every ten minutes.' Passing down a stairway at the right of this sign the traveler finds himself at the beginning of an inclined walk that seems interminable for distance, and leads down, down, further and further, 
  into the depths of earth. At last he arrives at a platform quite similar in appearance to those of the underground railway, only, I am happy to say, clean and new and well lighted, where the air is good. There, 
  after paying the few pennies required, he waits as patiently as he can for the advent of the train. At last it comes two long cars, with curved roofs to fit the arched roof of the tunnel. Entrance is from the sides and the rear, 
  as on the Brooklyn Bridge cars. After what appears to be an unnecessarily long wait the train starts. The speed is not great, and as the passage has few curves the journey is most delightful, there being nothing of the whirr, 
  noise, and sudden bumps which one sometimes experiences in the Boston subway
  </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>