<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-women-aviation</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042373/1910-09-01/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Up to the date of writing there had not been many women aviators.
  Italy had the Duchess of Aosta, cousin by marriage of King Victor Emmanuel. 
  France, in some respects the leader in aviation and in many respects the world's mentor in 'feminism,' had only three prominent lady fliers—Baroness de la Roche, incapacitated for an indefinite length of time by very serious injuries due to a fall, Mme. 
  Franck, also injured just after she had announced her intention of making a flight across the English Channel, and Mme. Paulhan, wife of the famous Louis. There have been a few others, but their exploits have attracted little attention. 
  England has two or three women fliers in heavier-than-air machines. Germany has produced no women fliers of note—none, that is, in aeroplanes. The Zeppelin, Parseval, and Gross dirigible balloons have had female passengers in some of their famous flights. 
  In America, we have had Miss Katherine Wright, Mrs. Hart O. Berg, Mrs. Cortland Field Bishop, Mrs. Clifford B. Harmon, Mrs. William K. Vanderbilt, Jr., and a few others as passengers with the 'man-birds' when they made flights above the earth. 
  Mrs. Bishop was the first woman to fly in America. But no American woman so far as known has been daring enough to go aloft as an aviator. 
  That will come in time, no doubt, and in the meanwhile, we may rest content with the fact that we have the only genuine, bona fide woman airship inventor on earth. She is worth a separate paragraph.

  Only Woman Airship Inventor
  The name of the lady is Miss E. Lillian Todd, and her post office address is New York. She is called 'probably the first woman in the world to design and build an aeroplane' all by herself. 
  The Todd machine was a collapsible or folding aeroplane, and the fact of its existence was first made public two years ago. Since that time Miss Todd has kept busy designing and making improvements to her aeroplane. 
  She is a member of the Aero Club of America and one of the founders of the Junior Aero Club, which aims at teaching the young American idea how to fly. Miss Todd has the added distinction of being the builder of her flying machine as well as its inventor. 
  Recently she had the good fortune to attract the notice of Mrs. Russell Sage, and it was announced that there was a fair chance of some of old Mr. Sage's carefully hoarded money being burnt up in gasoline and oil to run the Todd machine."
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1910-10-16/ed-1/seq-56/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  In the course of ten or twenty years, it may be as superfluous to talk about women who ride in flying machines as it would be now to go on about women who ride in streetcars. In the year 1910, however, a woman aviator is still a novelty. 
  The International Aviation Tournament at Belmont Park will be an exclusively masculine affair, and the heroism of those women who have begun to mount up with wings like eagles occasions a great deal of surprise, though it is hard to see why it should be so.
  Nobody is surprised when women drive automobiles, and in the matter of accidents, automobiles are up to the wire with anything that travels. Women are generally where the danger is. It was not until last November, however, that a woman actually went aloft alone. 
  Women had frequently gone as passengers with aviators of the other sex, but it remained for the Baronne Raymonde de Laroche to strike out in a new field as the first 'woman navigator through air currents.' This she did at Mourmelon. By now she is a veteran at the sport. 
  At the flying contests held in Egypt last spring, no one was more venturesome than she. The very first woman who ever flew was a Flemish girl, Mlle. P. von Pottelsberghe. She chanced to be on the field as a spectator when Henri Farman was making one of his first exhibition flights in Belgium. 
  A lightweight passenger was needed, and Mlle. von Pottelsberghe volunteered. Not very long afterward, at Turin, the French aviator, Mme. Thérèse Peltier, took a flight with Léon Delagrange in his Voisin biplane. Mme. 
  Peltier was very enthusiastic about the biplane then and was going to learn to drive it, but she never did. Probably the tragic death of Delagrange gave her a dislike for the sport. The first woman in America to fly was Mrs. Ralph Van Deman, wife of an army captain. 
  She has done all sorts of daring things. She is said to be able to ride any horse that goes, and when one of the Wrights invited her to go aloft with him near Washington last October, she jumped at the chance. Miss Katherine Wright, sister of the famous brothers, has ascended with them, but that was at Pau, and not in America.

  Of course, Mrs. Glenn H. Curtiss has had trips in her husband’s biplanes with him. She is her husband’s right hand, by the way, in his work of constructing biplanes. She attends to the business details, being fortunate enough to have a mother who manages the house, leaving her free to help her husband. 
  Women professionals are appearing in the flying field. Hélène Dutrieu is a bird-woman who has filled engagements to appear at amusement fields in a biplane. She holds the record among women aviators for distance and altitude, 
  having made a return flight from Ostend, Belgium, to Bruges with a passenger, a distance of twenty-eight miles, and gone up thirteen hundred feet. Mlle. Dutrieu has done nearly everything daring there was to do.

  Mme. Frank, another French woman, also has a record for long flights, and is now planning to fly across the English Channel.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1911-07-02/ed-1/seq-9/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  WOMEN WHO FLY
  When women take to aeroplane racing, as it is announced will be done at the summer meet of the Harvard Aeronautical Society in Cambridge, Mass., it will be only a matter of a short time before the interest in the sport will be so general that airship contests will be as common as tennis tourneys and golf competitions are today.
  Three countries will be represented by women contestants at Cambridge, with Mile. Dutrieu, a French airwoman of considerable experience, in the lead. Mrs. James V. Martin will wear the English colors; and Miss Emily Willard, who has already made several ascents with her brother at Mineola, 
  L. I., is, up to date, the third woman entered for the race. Mile. Dutrieu is looked upon as perhaps the most daring woman aviator in the world, although several of her own countrywomen press her closely for second place. She first began to fly in a Demoiselle monoplane about two years ago. 
  She changed to a Farman biplane; and it was in the latter machine that she made her longest flight, winning the Coupe Fémina after making 105 miles and remaining in the air for two hours and 35 minutes.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87093220/1911-08-03/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Mrs. Russell Sage has announced herself a patron of aviation. So interested is she in the doings of the flymen that she took a motor spin to Mineola, where the Aeronautic Society houses a dozen men and biplanes in a big red shed, and looked over all the engine-driven birds. 
  Especially was she interested in the big biplane being built by Miss E. L. Todd, the woman aviator. "It is very gratifying," said Mrs. Sage, speaking of Miss Todd's effort, "to see women take up these things, and I am always willing to encourage anything that is done by a woman. 
  I have watched Miss Todd's progress with much concern and hope she will succeed in making a successful flying machine." Miss E. Lilian Todd of New York is probably the first woman in the world to design and build an aeroplane. 
  This was a collapsible device, which she first made known to the public in the summer of 1908. It is believed that Miss Katherine Wright, sister of the Wright brothers, was the first American woman to make a flight in an aeroplane. 
  This she did on Feb. 15, 1909, at Pau, France, when she made an ascent with a brother, Mr. Wilbur Wright. To Mme. Raymonde de Laroche, who is a French baroness, belongs the distinction of being the pioneer woman aviator of France. 
  She was one of the first women to take a practical interest in aviation and soon after the first International Cup event at Rheims purchased a Voisin biplane.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1911-08-06/ed-1/seq-52/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Miss Matilda Moisant, sister of the late John Moisant, is learning to fly a monoplane.
  Three birdwomen, Miss Matilda Moisant, Miss Harriet Quimby, and Miss Blanche Stuart Scott, are the first Americans of their sex to take up aviation at Mineola. They all began their training under experienced pil
  Miss Harriet Quimby is the first American woman to receive an aviator's license. She and Miss Moisant are practicing their flights in monoplanes, while Miss Scott is flying a biplane. Miss Quimby and Miss Moisant seem to be more daring, participating in races and performing risky maneuvers. 
  Miss Quimby is determined and seems entirely at ease during her flights, despite the risks involved.
  Miss Blanche Stuart Scott, a more reserved figure compared to the others, is mastering the biplane under careful supervision. The excitement of flying captivates these women, and despite the public skepticism, they continue to pursue aviation with enthusiasm and determination.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88084272/1911-12-15/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Miss Moisant, in her aeroplane. She is the sister of John B. Moisant, the famous aviator killed in New Orleans, La., by his machine falling. Miss Moisant is ambitious to take her brother’s former place in the aviation world.
  Miss Harriet Quimby, the first woman aviator to receive a pilot's license from the Aero Club of America, has been followed by Miss Matilda Moisant, sister of John B. Moisant. 
  According to Professor Rudolph Hensingmuller, women are better suited for aviation than men. He cites several reasons:
  Women's greater peripheral vision, which is better adapted for flying as it closely resembles the sight of birds.
  Scattered attention instead of concentration, allowing women to notice many things at once—an essential quality for flying.
  Intuition, enabling women to rapidly perceive multiple factors and deduce conclusions in real-time.
  Lighter specific gravity, meaning women's bones are lighter than men's, making them better suited for the air.
  Hensingmuller believes that women’s heightened sensitivity to atmospheric changes and their lighter manner of sneezing—controlled by ages of social repression—also give them an advantage in aviation.
  On the contrary, Claude Grahame-White, a prominent English aviator, argues that women are temperamentally unfit for aviation. He believes they lack the coolness and concentration required for safe flying. 
  Grahame-White acknowledges that women have so far avoided serious accidents but attributes this to their limited flying experience, confined to aerodromes rather than cross-country flights, which present far more hazards. 
  He suggests that women might become better aviators when aviation becomes safer, but doubts they will dominate the skies.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn99021999/1913-04-13/ed-1/seq-21/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Mlle. Hélène Dutrieu, the "Hawk Girl of France," has just been made a Chevalier of the Legion of Honor as a reward for her skill as an aviator. Mlle. Dutrieu is one of the few women to receive this prestigious decoration. 
  France awarded her this honor because the Bureau of War has become convinced that women make better aviators than men, encouraging more women to enter aviation. 
  Harriet Quimby, the queen of American flying women, is one of the few women to have tragically lost her life in aviation. Quimby, the first woman to receive a pilot's license in the United States, is remembered as a pioneering figure in American aviation.
  The French War Department conducted tests showing that women have several advantages over men in aviation:
  Women are more primitive and have less delicate nerves, making them less nervous.
  Women feel pain less than men.
  Women need less oxygen, making them better suited for high-altitude flying.
  Women possess greater peripheral vision than men, allowing them to see more of their surroundings while flying.
  Diffused attention—the ability to manage multiple tasks at once—is a natural trait of women, making them more adept at flying.
  Women have lighter bones and less specific gravity, which gives them an advantage in controlling an aircraft.
  Women’s sneezes are less violent, which is an important factor when flying at high altitudes.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1914-07-07/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  "Flying is no job for women and never will be! Nature herself has forbidden them to risk their lives foolishly in the air. Through the mother instinct in them Nature will hold them always close to mother earth."
  It was one of the most expert of the world's six licensed birdwomen who, at my question, thus excluded the rest of her sex from participation in the great air game of which she herself is a master.
  Mrs. Richberg Hornsby of Chicago is the first and only pupil of Orville Wright.
  "The prettiest flying I ever saw a beginner do!" was Wright's exclamation, twice repeated, during Mrs. Hornsby's trials.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038615/1914-11-01/ed-1/seq-51/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  PROPOSAL has been made to organize a corps of women aviators to serve with the allied armies of England and France, now fighting the Germans. 
  The idea has been received with enthusiasm by many women, who reject the ancient theory of feminine weakness and declare that their sex is fully as fit to face peril as the men.
  The aviators have proved themselves one of the most valuable factors in the war. There is a great need of more of them, and it is impossible to train them in a hurry. 
  This is one of the strongest reasons urged in favor of using the many skilled women aviators in the fighting. 
  The suggestion has actually appeared in print that Lady Victoria May Pery, daughter of the Earl of Limerick, should become chief of a British royal feminine flying corps.
  Lady Victoria is one of the most dashing and certainly the prettiest of English women aviators. She was trained in aviation by Grahame White and the late, Gustav Hamel, in whose company she "looped the loop" in a most daring manner. 
  Hamel was eventually killed while doing this trick. It is not likely, however, that Lady Victoria will take the suggestion and join the fighting aviation corps, for she has gone to the United States and there become the bride of Mr. James C. Brady.
  We have probably not yet reached the point where a bride will interrupt her honeymoon to go off to the war, after the fashion of the German submarine captain who left his bride of the before to steam away and blow up three British warships.
  There are, however, plenty of English women and French women without encumbrances who are ready to fight in the air corps. Why should not women serve as military aviators? They have the courage and the skill. They have the patriotism. 
  If they are inferior in weight and muscle to men, these qualities are not of the first importance to the aviator. In steadiness and nerve, which are the essential qualities in the air, the modern girl claims to be fully the equal of her brother.
  One of the most daring of women aviators is Mademoiselle Helene Dutrieu, of France. She was the first woman to perform the loop-the-loop trick, that "death-defying stunt" that made men's blood stand still when they first saw a man do it. 
  Mademoiselle Dutrieu did it as coolly and cleverly as any man. She is a tall, slender girl with an exquisite figure, as supple as a bamboo and as strong as steel. She has carried a man passenger very often, and is therefore well qualified for war aviation, 
  in which two persons in a machine are almost a necessity. Mademoiselle Dutrieu received the Legion of Honor decoration for her exploits. She would undoubtedly make a daring leader of fighting aviators. Among the many brilliant French airwomen are Madame Francis, 
  Mademoiselle Julienne Marehl, the Baroness Raymonde de la Roche, Mademoiselle Marvingt, and Mademoiselle Valentine Duels. The Baroness Raymonde de la Roche started flying at Mourmelon and broke her arm in one of her first flights. 
  In Egypt, she flew over the Sphinx and the Pyramids. At St. Petersburg, she flew over the city and was warmly congratulated by the Czar. She flew over Budapest in Hungary. In one of her first attempts, she came near having a fatal accident, 
  and many people thought the experience would rob her of her nerve completely. She was carried by the wind over a clump of trees. She did her best to avoid them with a swift turn of the aeroplane rudder, but the machine, rushing through the air at express-train speed, 
  touched the topmost branches, and with a whirling crash it came sweeping to the ground and was wrecked irretrievably. Instantly, the spectators rushed to the spot, expecting to pick up the body of the aviator, 
  but the Baroness extricated herself from the debris quite unhurt and not at all frightened. Indeed, she laughed at the startled faces about her and said calmly: "An uncomfortable experience, it is true, but I rather expected it."
  The next day she was in the air again with a new machine. Mademoiselle Marvingt began her training with two men, Wachter and Laffont, who were subsequently killed. This did not daunt her, and she went on and won a cup for flying women. 
  Miss Eleanor Trehawko Davies has the reputation of being the most daring of English aviatrices. She has flown across the English Channel several times. On one occasion, when crossing with Gustav Hamel, 
  she saved them both by working the second pressure pump when he was partly benumbed with cold, at a height of 8,000 feet. Mrs. Gavin is another daring English woman who has flown across the Channel. She practiced aviation in the part of France where the war is now raging, 
  and could give valuable assistance to the army. Miss Spencer Kavanagh has also distinguished herself as an aviator. Miss Kavanagh has also been a sportswoman, having hunted, broken horses, driven automobiles in races, and gone in for athletic contests. She wished to learn to 
  fly as soon as it became known that it was a possible achievement and went to Pau, determined to master the art. Women who are learning to fly are sometimes taught on a rather peculiar mechanism, which is arranged to operate like an aeroplane but has no wings. It has all the 
  controls like an aeroplane and runs about on the ground like an automobile. By permitting the pupil to absorb the feel of riding in an aeroplane, it is possible to save her some bruises, perhaps broken bones, and costly repairs to the flying machine.
  A French scientist, Dr. Babin, has recently demonstrated that women are better fitted for flying than men for several reasons:
  Because women are more primitive than men.
  Their nerves are not so delicate, and so they are less nervous.
  They feel pain less than men do.
  They need less oxygen in their breathing.
  The arc of their sight is nearly double that of men.
  They have the faculty of "diffused attention," which men ordinarily lack.
  Their specific gravity is less than men's, and the slight differences in their skeletal structure give them an enormous advantage in the air over their heavier, more compact male counterparts.
  Their sneezes are less violent.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1915-07-18/ed-1/seq-33/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Miss Moisant was the next American woman after her friend Miss Quimby to be granted a pilot's license. She attributes her good fortune in her flights to her lucky number 13, which was always attached to her machine. She was taught to fly by her famous brother. 
  Once, she escaped from an angry sheriff by aeroplane.
  Blanche Stuart Scott was first noticed for her excellent driving during a transcontinental trip in one of the Glidden tours as a motorist. She later learned aviation at the Curtiss school and made a record cross-country flight to Garden City, Long Island.
  Pernetta Adams Miller is a young American pilot from the Moisant school, flying a Bleriot-type monoplane. She represents one of about fifty women fliers at that time, with an accident rate no higher than that of men aviators.
  Mathilde Moisant was involved in a burning machine accident while flying at Wichita, Texas. She was rescued from the wreckage, and the event was captured in a photograph taken by an amateur.
  Harriet Quimby, a journalist, witnessed an aeroplane race for the first time in 1910. Two months later, she became an efficient pilot. Quimby was the first American woman to receive a pilot's license, the first to steer a monoplane, and the first woman to cross the English Channel. 
  She tragically met her death in 1912 at Boston.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85059732/1915-08-01/ed-1/seq-32/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  HELENA DUTRIEU, the "Girl Hawk," upon whom appreciative France has bestowed the decoration of the Legion of Honor, is surely one of the most modest of heroines and is less inclined to dwell upon the fact that she has the distinction of being the first woman air scout in history than she is to discuss generally the use of the aeroplane in war.
  She is a girl in vivacity and enthusiasms. She recently was in this country in the interests of the Red Cross.
  An Unofficial Flyer
  She is not regularly enrolled in the army, and, though she gladly would die for her country, she has no desire to become a soldier. That the government receives her services unofficially gives her no offense at all. She fully agrees with the Frenchman's point of view on the sex question.
  "He does not want his wife to fight," she explains. "He will not permit her life to be endangered. He will not be responsible for her death. Not that the French woman is not brave. All women are brave when the lives of their dear ones are threatened. But especially the French woman. I think, for she is more emotional."
  Gave Warning Thrice.
  Mile. Dutrieu would make you believe that some of the perils through which she passed in times of peace far overshadow those of the war period, and laughs when she quotes a report that her duty was to chase away the raiding German Taubes that dropped bombs upon Paris. "All I did was to fly up when 
  I suspected that the German airmen were coming," she explained, "and, then, if I observed the enemy approaching, return and report to the men, who immediately rose to give battle or chase to the intruder."
  Three times when the Germans were advancing on Paris did she give warning of their approach, her swift monoplane affording her a long advantage over the enemy. "There was no danger," she says simply.
  Bruges Chimed Her Honors.
  She had already fallen from a house during an accident in Odessa and escaped without serious hurt. Her monoplane had turned turtle with her at Issy-les-Moulineaux and she escaped only with a severe shaking up, having been saved by the upper stays of the machine. She has had many another close call.
  The record of this incident tells us that: "The mayor and all the officers of the city led in the shower of congratulations that fell upon Mile. Dutrieu. Thus they pressed around the girl and the flying machine. And so she had to be protected—so many desired to kiss her."
  She was the first woman to fly into Belgium. Two officers only had done so before her. And over the air lanes that she sailed in her journey of a new achievement 
  "Nervous?" she repeated the query, smiled and was silent for a moment. "My friend, one must not be nervous in the upper air, or one will never go there again. The true aviator must be without nerves."
  She’s a Homing Bird.
  The first woman air scout became interested in flying about eight years ago, and, noting her youthful appearance now, one estimates that she must have been a slip of a girl when the fusillading motor sent the earth away from beneath her for the first time.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89074405/1915-08-02/ed-1/seq-11/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  "THREE things prompted me to volunteer for air scouting over Paris after the war began," said pretty, diminutive and effeminate Helene Dutrieu, the French aviatrix, who is now in this country.
  “I love France. I love adventure. I knew my business. Most of the men fliers were needed at the front in strictly military reconnaissance work. There were comparatively few aviators available for guarding Paris. I told the military government I wanted to do my part. They told me that I could 
  not be entered upon the army rolls; that I could not have any official position, but that I might work privately. So from the day the war began I was in the air practically every day, sometimes arising early in the morning and scouting for hours, sometimes flying in the afternoon or late evening. I had the good fortune on numerous occasions 
  to detect taubes on their way to visit Paris, and I was able to descend and warn the aviation corps commanders so that they had ample time to send up squadrons and fight off or frighten away the invaders.
  “I am sorry I cannot say that the Germans shot at me. But I never let their fliers get close enough to shoot at my machine or to drop bombs on me. I circled around and around, keeping watch with my glasses, and the instant I detected a German machine I darted to earth and gave warning. Usually I flew at a height of from 1,500 to 2,000 meters, 
  but sometimes I had to go much higher because of fogs and mists that veiled the lower altitudes."
  Mile. Dutrieu is so girlish in appearance that she does not look her age, which, as she remarked very naively, "is between twenty-five and thirty." Certainly the reporter who talked with her would have been perfectly willing to accept the smaller figure. She has been, as she puts it, "trying to die young" ever since she was in her teens.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1919-04-22/ed-1/seq-11/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Fair Aviatrices Fly to Aid Loan
  Did you see the ladies in the airplanes yesterday?
  If you did, you saw some real 'stunts' both in flying and selling Victory Liberty Loan bonds. If you didn't you lost a good chance not only of seeing a spectacular performance, but also the distinction of being sold bonds by the fair flyers.
  If you weren't there yourself, thousands of Washingtonians were on hand at Polo Field, in Potomac Park, yesterday to greet the three women flyers as they swooped down upon them and landed in their midst. Victory bonds in one hand and literature on the subject in the other.
  And the women were not a bit scared, either. They said they enjoyed the experience of flying from Anacostia to Polo Field.
  The daring flyers were Mrs. Charlotte B. Eldridge, Miss Marjorie Stinson, and Mrs. Brice Clagett, all members of the District's Woman's Liberty Loan Committee. Mrs. Eldridge sold a $5,000 bond right off the reel, from the cockpit of her machine, a Martin bomber, which was piloted by Capt. Roy N. Francis.
  Not to be outdone, Mrs. Clagett sold a $1,000 Victory bond a few minutes later to C. Erlebacher, and business was brisk after that, the day's total for the women's committee being $20,000 obtained in loan subscriptions.
  Miss Billie Burke, who motored down to the field in a car loaned by Miss Mabel Boardman, also got busy and sold several hundred dollars' worth of bonds.
  Disdaining the services of a full-fledged pilot, Miss Marjorie Stinson skillfully guided a small Curtiss plane between Boiling Field and Potomac Park and upon landing sold $3,000 worth of bonds.
  </text>
      </result>

# Ten additional documents from Chronicling America
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90061308/1913-01-17/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84024283/1915-12-09/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1943-09-19/ed-1/seq-70/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Woman, 63, a Pilot in 1912, Now a Metal Worker Repairing Planes for ATC
  By Gretchen Smith.
  The love of aviation which enabled Mrs. Alys McKey Bryant to fly a plane built of “bamboo and bits of wire” in 1912 has increased with the passing of years. Today, at the age of 63, she is 
  one of the most air-minded workers at the National Airport, where she is employed by TWA as a metal worker repairing planes for the Air Transport Command.
  An energetic, friendly little woman, Mrs. Bryant spoke of her past work and her faith in the future of aviation as she chatted outside the hangar, attired in khaki overalls, 
  an overseas cap pulled smartly over short, gray hair.
  “Everything is going to be aviation after this war,” she commented. “I don’t see why women and girls don't all get into this aviation and mechanical game. They should get into some branch 
  of it and learn to fly. Planes are so simple today that anyone should be able to fly.
  “Friends say I was born with wings,” she laughed. “When I was 12 years old, back in 1892, I lived on a prairie in Indiana and being very much alone, I daydreamed a lot. 
  I wrote a composition at that time describing an imaginary flight in an airplane from the East Coast to California, never realizing such a thing would some day be an everyday affair.”
  Mrs. Bryant’s dreams of flying were realized in 1912 when she answered an advertisement in a Los Angeles paper.
  “It was an ad for a young woman willing to fly,” she explained. “Out of 65 who answered, I was selected to learn to do stunt flying for my employer. I was given a plane that had crashed 
  a short time before and had been reconstructed. It was built of bamboo, muslin, bits of wire, and bicycle wheels,” she laughed. “It had a Curtis V-8 motor and we carried 5 gallons of gas.”
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038485/1910-09-11/ed-1/seq-24/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  It is doubtful whether even the long list of fatalities and accidents that have attended the aviation experiments of this year will in any way intercept the great interest taken in flying—especially by women, 
  who crowd to all the flying meetings. Indeed, from the very early days of aviation, women have shown their keen interest in the new sport. Miss Wright, the only sister of the famous Wright brothers, 
  has been very interested in aeronautics for years past and has relinquished all other amusement and enjoyments in order to devote herself to the success of her brothers' experiments.
  Mrs. Henry Farman is another woman keenly interested in flying experiments, who has an intimate knowledge of every detail of her husband’s aeroplane.
  Amongst society women interested in the new sport is the Countess Kinnoull, who is on the committee of a society composed of well-known women who pledge themselves to do all that they can to establish a fleet of airships.
  Lady Granard is credited with having ordered an aeroplane, while another lady of title (if rumor is to be believed) is prepared to finance a cross-channel flying service. Well-known aeronauts are most optimistic concerning 
  feminine interest in flying matters. "Once a woman takes airships up, they will go ahead," said one recently. For it is a well-known fact that the success of the automobile was assured when women took it up. 
  The same thing holds good in regard to the bicycle, and it will hold good with regard to the airships.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045396/1910-09-11/ed-1/seq-33/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  It is doubtful whether even the long list of fatalities and accidents that have attended the aviation experiments of this year will in any way interrupt the great interest taken in flying, especially by women, 
  who crowd to all the flying meetings. Indeed, from the very early days of aviation, women have shown their keen interest in the new sport. Miss Wright, the only sister of the famous Wright brothers, has been 
  very interested in aeronautics for years past and has relinquished all other amusements and enjoyments in order to devote herself to the success of her brothers' experiments.
  Mrs. Henry Farman is another woman keenly interested in flying experiments, who has an intimate knowledge of every detail of her husband’s aeroplane.
  Among society women interested in the new sport is the Countess Kinnoull, who is on the committee of a society composed of well-known women who pledge themselves to do all that they can to establish a fleet of airships.
  Lady Granard is credited with having ordered an aeroplane, while another lady of title (if rumor is to be believed) is prepared to finance a cross-channel flying service. Well-known aeronauts are most optimistic 
  concerning feminine interest in flying matters. "Once a woman takes airships up, they will go ahead," said one recently. For it is a well-known fact that the success of the automobile was assured when women took it up. 
  The same thing holds good in regard to the bicycle, and it will hold good with regard to the airships.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1944-03-26/ed-1/seq-61/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Babs Beckwith is saying gikxl-by to glamour, hello to a new career in aviation.
  As you can tell from any one ofour pictures, Babs is a rare looker. For years, she led the parade as one of the most successful models around. She was also an aviation bug. When her face and figure landed her in
  Hollywood, she had to make a choice. An attractive movie contract was waved at her. But it had a proviso — no flying. Reason: her cautious producer was afraid to spend a fortune. building her up and then have his
  property flit around the country in airplanes.
  Babs thought it over — and went to Miami determined to fly.
  Cautious Parent
  The lady already had her private pilot’s' license. She got it in 1941. Her first passenger was her father. He is a devoted and proud parent, but before he set foot in Babs's plane,
  he solemnly bade farewell to all his friends, kissed a rabbit’s foot, demanded — and got — three parachutes. Since then, however, Babs has gone far. She first acquired her commercial pilot’s license, followed
  that with an instructor’s rating which lets her teach fledgling pilots how to fly. After the war, she wants to be a commercial pilot. “There’ll be plenty of women in aviation jobs — and I’ll be one of the first of
  them, I hope.’’ Babs is very serious about her work. Seven a m. — no decent hour for a cafe-society celebrity—is start ing time for her at the Embry-Riddle School, where she got her instructor's
  training. And she does a man’s full sized job before quitting time each day. Now that she has her instructor’s ticket, she is working harder than ever, teaching Army Air Corps pilots how to fly.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1948-08-29/ed-1/seq-113/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  Helen B. McGilvery, 31, is one of the few woman airport managers in the country. Nor is she just a desk-sitting figurehead whose only interest in flying is academic. She is a flying executive who can handle a rubber stamp or a control stick with equal facility.
  Miss McGilvery has been flying for about eight years, and has about 2,400 hours to her credit. She put in long service with the WASPS during the war. This organization of woman pilots performed prodigiously in ferrying planes around the country for the Air Force. 
  Miss McGilvery flew pursuit planes mostly.
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85059586/1918-12-06/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86091218/1911-10-20/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
  </text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1963-11-13/ed-1/seq-82/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
  The Top-Side Aviation Club, women of the aviation industry in Washington, will hold their annual election meeting at the Madison next Tuesday at 6 p.m. It's members only.
  </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>