<topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-x-rays/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1896-02-18/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	Professor Fernando Sanford of the department of physics of the Stanford University has just received a letter from his associate, Professor Carmen, who is now in Berlin, 
	and who has investigated Roentgen's photographs with his X or unknown rays. Professor Carmen doesn't say very much, but what he does say comes from a scientist.
	"I saw Roentgen's photographs the other day," writes Carmen in the course of his letter, "and heard Warburg, professor of physics in the University of Berlin, 
	and others discuss them. Lummer had also seen them, and there seems to be no doubt about the reality of the phenomenon. The photograph of the hand, 
	in which only the bones and the ring are shown, is very striking. It is, however, not very sharp. A photograph of a magnetic compass in a wooden case, 
	photographed through the case, is very sharp indeed. We know as much here as anywhere, but there is yet no consensus of opinion as to what the phenomenon really is. 
	The natural idea is that they are longitudinal ether waves. They are, however, very faint."
	Professor Sanford talked about Roentgen's work, explaining, "The scientists are only guessing at the new thing yet, though many have opinions."
    Sanford further explained that Roentgen’s discovery might be related to "a new form of motion or vibration in the ether—vibrations that are longitudinal 
	instead of transverse to the line of progress." He added that many scientists were still speculating about the phenomenon.
	Sanford described a Crookes tube and its function in producing fluorescence, stating that such a tube could also produce Roentgen's X-ray photographs. 
	He explained that X-rays, or vibrations of some sort, were beaming from the Crookes tube in all directions. He also emphasized that these rays were not 
	light and that they produced shadow effects, as seen in Roentgen's photographic results, such as the shadow of bones seen through flesh.
    Sanford continued by explaining how Roentgen accidentally discovered that a certain sheet of paper, moistened with a specific chemical compound, 
	fluoresced when near a covered Crookes tube. This led to his famous discovery that the rays could pass through materials, such as wood and flesh, 
	producing images of internal structures like bones.
    Sanford also noted that Roentgen’s theory was that the gaseous particles striking against the glass in the tube might produce a new form of wave 
	or vibration in the ether, which he believed to be longitudinal waves. These X-rays could not be reflected, refracted, or polarized, as light waves can be, 
	which led Roentgen to believe they represented a new kind of radiation. However, Sanford mentioned that the full implications of Roentgen's discovery for 
	science and practical use were still unknown but of great interest.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025121/1896-09-11/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	Dr. Lauschner proceeded with his talk and demonstrations on the Roentgen or "X-Ray." He emphasized that the discovery of the X-ray had created one of the greatest 
	sensations ever made by discoveries in the realm of science.
	Dr. Lauschner explained the apparatus for photographing by means of the "X-Ray," noting that each part of the apparatus had been employed before in other scientific 
	experiments. The components include the electric current, the induction coil, and the Crookes tube. He mentioned that the Crookes tube had been used by Prof. 
	Crookes for a number of years, taken up by Lenard, and lastly employed by Roentgen.
	The discovery of the "X-Ray" was not merely accidental. Roentgen had experimented with the cathode ray terminal and, during these experiments, 
	discovered what he found to be a new force. At first, Roentgen thought that the force must be some modification of the cathode ray, 
	but he realized it was something entirely new. The "X" in X-Ray represents an unknown quantity—no one knows what it is or the nature of the ray. 
	While its effects and some products of the ray are known, scientists are still trying to figure out its true nature.
	Dr. Lauschner highlighted that scientists have hesitated to make assertions about what the rays are because it might 
	require them to overthrow established theories that have existed for many years.
	The demonstration continued with Dr. Lauschner using a Crookes tube to display the effects of the X-rays. He held up a "screen" in front of the tube and placed his 
	hand between the tube and the screen. Immediately, the bones of his fingers and hand became visible. He also demonstrated how X-rays could penetrate a thick book 
	and reveal the contents of a pocketbook, including metal coins inside.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015104/1896-10-25/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	LOOKING INTO THE UNSEEN.
    The X Ray Experiments Rapidly Reaching Perfection.
	DR. WM. J. MORTON'S MARVELOUS RESULTS.
    Its Wonderful Aid to Hospitals and Surgeons in Locating Foreign Substances in the Human Frame—The Most Recent Investigations of the Great Inventors and Scientists, 
	Roentgen, Edison and Lodge—A Valuable Work on the Subject Which Has Made a Stir in the Scientific World.
	["The X Ray; or, Photography of the Invisible," copyrighted, 1896, by the American Technical Book Company, New York. All rights reserved.]
    Electricity has contributed much to our present advanced civilization; much which the world could not well do without; but, if much of that which has been contributed were swept away, 
	leaving only its last, greatest and most wonderful achievement, the X ray discovery, the world could bear the loss. There are substitutes for them; but none for the X ray.
    The telegraph, telephone, electric light and electric railway, as factors in the world's progress, have done wonders in bringing nations and individuals nearer together and increasing 
	the volume of business transacted in a given length of time, but even these are limited in their scope, while the province of the X ray is world-wide.
    As demonstrated by the experiments of Dr. William J. Morton and others, this light, to which nearly all so-called opaque materials are as transparent as glass is to the ordinary daylight, 
	enables the physician and surgeon to look into the human frame as one looks into a room through a window.
    Scarcely has this discovery been published to the world by Professor Roentgen, when thousands of men of all professions are busily engaged in experimenting toward the perfection of its 
	production and the multiplication of its useful applications. And thousands more are awaiting information which will enable them to handle this beneficent gift intelligently.
    Never, perhaps, in all history has a discovery so far-reaching in its effects upon the well-being of humanity in general been brought before the world. It makes surgery an exact science, 
	and places the healing art far beyond the groping amid fleeting symptoms into the realms of certainty. Wherever disease or accident have preyed upon or marred the integrity of the human form, 
	its members or organs, there will this greatest wonder of the nineteenth century, like a ministering angel, fold its wings and shower its blessings.
    Almost as wonderful as the discovery of the X rays is the fact that within a few months after its announcement the press is spreading broadcast the latest and most complete information upon 
	the subject from the pens of those whose names have become household words throughout the civilized world. Edison, Tesla, Lodge, Morton, and others are speaking to the great public on this 
	wonderfully interesting subject through a timely contribution to popular scientific literature entitled "The X Ray; or, Photography of the Invisible and Its Value in Surgery," published by 
	the American Technical Book Company, 45 Vesey street. The work is by Dr. William J. Morton, the famous X ray expert, in collaboration with E. W. Hammer, electrical engineer.
    The names of the authors are a guarantee of the excellence of the work; both gentlemen standing high in their individual professions.
    Aside from his standing as one of the leaders in the medical profession, Dr. Morton has been identified with Professor Roentgen's discovery as one of the earliest and most active experimenters 
	in this new field, and with the most fully equipped X ray laboratory, has justified all expectations by producing a large number of the finest X ray photographs thus far produced in the world. 
	Not content with hands, feet and other minor portions of the body, he has taken photographs of the entire trunk, pelvis, etc., which have been by competent authorities, pronounced wonderful in 
	their perfection of detail, and of inestimable value in surgical operations.
    Mr. Hammer is a practical electrician of large experience, both in this country and abroad.
    "The X ray, or Photography of the Invisible," gives a clear and exact explanation of the theory of the X rays, as well as the method of arranging and operating the apparatus involved in their production. 
	To this end the work commences by explaining in simple language and comparison with well-known objects the nature of electricity, the method of and means for measuring it and the various means and devices 
	for generating and controlling it, each and all of the devices referred to being carefully illustrated and described.
    Step by step, the reader is carried from one point of interest and information to another, until every detail of theory, practice, process and implement is made clear, and anyone of ordinary intelligence may, 
	by acting carefully upon the information conveyed, produce perfect X ray photographs.
    To the physician, far away from the great centers of learning, who must rely entirely upon himself for all that is necessary of intelligence and mechanical skill to carry out his experiments, 
	this work will prove invaluable.
	To the electrician and amateur it is a clear guide; each step being laid down by men who have, so to speak, paced off the entire road from start to finish.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1897-04-25/ed-1/seq-19/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	THE LATEST PHASES OF X-RAY INVESTIGATION
    Why the Mysterious Radiance Is Visible to Some Blind People
    Instead of diminishing as the days go by, interest in the X-ray is constantly on the increase and any new theory as to its origin, action, or results is eagerly seized upon by medical men, electricians, 
	and the public in general. In some ways, the X-ray has not proved all that was expected a year ago, but in others, it has surpassed the wildest conjectures as to its possibilities. 
	It has been shown that it is not a plaything to be used by anybody, and it has also been demonstrated that in experienced hands, its field is almost boundless.
    Ever since Professor Roentgen made the discovery of the existence of the X-ray, scientific men have constantly been experimenting to ascertain why the wonderful radiance is invisible to a normal eye. 
	Powerful enough to pass with ease through a piece of three-inch oak, the human eye cannot see it. While it is shown that a space of many cubic feet around an active Crookes tube must be a perfect glow of light, 
	as far as the human eye is concerned, it is perfect darkness. Truly, this is mysterious.
    For a long time, the generally accepted theory was that the vibrations of the X-rays were too rapid for the human sense of vision to grasp. It was estimated that this was a trillion times the vibration of ordinary 
	white light in daylight. Then came the astonishing statement that many blind people experienced the sensation of light on looking at a working Crookes tube. To be sure, they saw no objects, but the fact that they 
	were able to distinguish light was something wonderful.
    Charles Guillaume, an eminent scientist of France, has just issued a circular regarding this aspect of the X-ray that seems reasonable in many ways. Experiments have also been made in this city that show the 
	correctness of his reasoning. A copy of the circular in question has been received by Professor Van der Naillen of the School of Engineering, and he has been only too willing to show it to those interested.
    In his circular, Guillaume states that he was led to his investigations by the acknowledged connection between the X-ray and the ultraviolet rays of the spectrum. It has been shown photographically that the ultraviolet rays exist, 
	and yet they cannot be seen by the human eye. Whether they are also capable of penetrating solids is still a matter of conjecture, owing to the lack of apparatus for collecting and separating them from the other colors of the spectrum.
    Following up his theory, Guillaume concluded that there was something in the normal eye that resisted the X-rays and prevented their reaching the nerve centers. The aqueous humor and crystalline lens of the eye are as transparent to ordinary 
	light as the finest window glass, but investigations show them to be as impervious to the X-ray as a piece of lead. This is why the rays cannot be seen.
    In many cases of blindness, particularly blindness caused by some accident, the optic nerve is in perfect condition, but the structure of the eyeball has changed. The greater portion of it has decayed and become, instead of a perfect piece of 
	mechanism and an arrangement of refractory atoms, merely a piece of organic matter like the tissue in many other parts of the body. In this condition, it is plainly seen that it will offer no more resistance to the X-ray than a portion of skin, 
	and that if the nerves are still perfect, the rays will reach them and the sensation of light will be conveyed to the brain.
    To ascertain the correctness of Guillaume's theory, several experiments were made for The Call on both normal and blind eyes. Professor Van der Naillen kindly loaned his apparatus for this purpose, and the results have been more than enough 
	to show that Guillaume is on the right track at least. What the future will develop remains to be seen.
    For these experiments, the eyeballs of different domestic animals were used, most of them being obtained in Butchertown as soon as the killing was done. There was the greatest uniformity of result observable in all the tests.
    In the first experiment, the naturally blind eye of a calf and also a normal eye of the same animal were placed side by side on the same plate and given exactly the same time of exposure. They were, of course, developed at the same time and printed on the same sheet of paper.
    The proof showed the normal eye simply as a dark spot, with a slight indication of the crystalline lens appearing a little darker than the other parts. The conclusion to be reached from this is that the rays could not pass through the eye. The blind eye, on the contrary, 
	freely permitted the passage of the X-rays and appeared quite light, with considerable differentiation of the layers. There was a slight indication of the lens and also several spots that were meaningless. But the difference between the two eyes was apparent at a glance.
    Experiments were also made with the eyes of sheep and rabbits, and the results were about the same in all cases. The normal eyes came out perfectly black in all instances, but the blind eyes showed different comparative shades, owing, of course, to the condition of the tissues.
    Experiments were also made with eyes artificially blinded. From some, the lens was removed, and others were injected with enough ammonia to destroy the nature of the tissue.
    On the whole, the results of these tests were similar to the others. The normal eyes showed dark, and the artificially blinded eyes permitted the passage of the rays in spots, possibly such spots as were acted on by the injected chemicals. The removal of the lens was clearly shown, 
	although the aqueous humor that remained showed as a dark plane.
    The eyes of sheep and rabbits did not give as good radiographs as those of calves and sheep, for the reason that they were much smaller, and the differentiation was not as plainly indicated. Still, in every instance, the results showed that the X-rays passed through the blind eyes, 
	more or less, but were resisted almost entirely by the healthy eyes.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88085190/1904-12-31/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	I am feeling poorly — very poorly. The old X-ray trouble is after me. It won’t let go. It killed my assistant. Yes, sir; killed him by inches. Now it’s after me. Knots all along my stomach — great big ones running in a semi-circle. Can’t eat anything nowadays. 
	It isn’t indigestion, either. The doctors don’t know what to make of it. Old Father Time will have to diagnose it I guess.
	The X-ray ailment developed several years ago while Edison was experimenting with the Roentgen rays. He it was who perfected the fluoroscope. An assistant named Dalley helped him in his work. Dalley had his face near the X-ray. Edison had the strange light near his stomach. 
	Dalley developed a cancer on his face. It killed him a month ago. Edison is now in constant fear of a cancer in his stomach. That is why he had to give up his X-ray experiments.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn93061430/1908-06-26/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	X-RAY OF AN ELEPHANT INTERIOR OP BIG BRUTE PHOTOGRAPHED.
	An effort was made to locate a diamond ring belonging to a man and swallowed by an elephant while being fed peanuts. Three expert X-ray operators and four elephant trainers worked together to photograph the interior of the elephant using the largest X-ray apparatus ever made. 
	The side of the elephant was marked in sections, and the trainers tried to determine where the ring might be lodged after developing the plates. It was the first time in the history of science that X-ray pictures of an elephant had been attempted.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1914-02-22/ed-1/seq-43/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	MORE POWERFUL X-RAYS
	All because of a peculiarly unyielding gray metal it has become possible to make a development of revolutionary character in the newest form of X-ray apparatus. The discovery is the result of the perseverance of Dr. William David Coolidge and his associates of the research 
	laboratory of the General Electric Company. Radiographers and radiotherapists declare this development of the X-ray tube to be the greatest discovery in the art since Prof. Wilhelm Konrad Roentgen in 1895 startled the world with his original announcement of an invisible beam 
	that could penetrate opaque bodies and make shadowgraphs of hidden objects.
	The metal in question is commonly known as tungsten, but it might better be called wolfram, the wilful, as this is the older name for it and the adjective attached quite fittingly characterizes the material. Dr. Coolidge’s X-ray tube is almost directly the consequence of 
	exhaustive efforts made to adapt tungsten for service as a filament for incandescent electric lights.
    Prior to this, the Roentgen tube was limited in its possibilities by the endurance of platinum, which was used for the target, or antlcathode, of the X-ray apparatus; limited because this target has to withstand intense heat to give off the most effective measure of deeply 
	penetrative rays, and the melting point of platinum is 3,195 degrees Fahrenheit. The only way to improve the X-ray output seemed to be to find a more refractory material for the target, one that had a higher melting point.
    Until the advent of pure malleable tungsten there was nothing to supplant the platinum, but then the situation was changed. Tungsten has a melting point nearly 60 percent higher than platinum, or, to be exact, 5,432 degrees Fahrenheit. To this extent, the substitution of 
	tungsten extended the possibilities of the Roentgen tube.
	From the cathode or negative element of the X-ray tube, cathode rays are driven forth to strike the interposed target or antlcathode. The more violently they are impelled against the target, the stronger the resulting X-rays coming from the antlcathode. But, unfortunately, 
	this produces heat, and if the attack is too impetuous or strong, the metal of the target may be raised to the melting point and scattered against the inner walls of the glass tube. Therefore, by substituting the more resistant tungsten, a very material gain was secured and
	more powerful X-rays were placed within the reach of the radiographer, the man of science, and the radio-therapist.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1915-09-05/ed-1/seq-29/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	RADIUM Cures X-RAY DISEASE in EARLY Stage
	Epithelioma, the dread and curse of the Roentgenologist, has been found, in its early stages, amenable to radium cure, so that a distinct step in the advancement of Roentgen-ray science has been achieved. Epithelioma is skin cancer caused by the X-ray and has been the cause 
	of the loss of fingers, hands, and even the lives of Roentgen-ray experts. At a recent meeting of the British Medical Association, the Roentgenologist section was notable for the large number of disfigured hands, arms, and faces. In some cases, epithelioma has spread to the 
	chin and chest. Skin grafting, freezing, and other desperate measures have been used in vain to arrest the course of the dread disease.
	It is now firmly established, however, that radium rays will cure the malady in its early stages, and relief has been obtained even when the disease had run a couple of years. The effect of radium on long-standing cancers, however, is nil.
    It seems almost a paradox of radiology that the accepted use of a heavy gamma radiation from a Roentgen tube will cause a diseased condition of the skin, which a similar radiation from a tube of radium will cure. The output of the Roentgen-ray tube is almost wholly composed of hard, 
	penetrating, irritating gamma rays. The radium discharges the beta ray in great quantity, as well as the gamma ray. It is the beta ray that has been proved beyond question to be the efficient curative power, and it is only the secondary betas generated by the gamma when striking any 
	resisting substances that give it its value in the Roentgen-ray tube work. Hence, a surface lesion of morbid cell growth, be it hyperkeratosis or basal cell, is cured by the large output of soft beta radiation of radium.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030272/1915-08-29/ed-1/seq-59/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	BURNLESS X-RAY CLAIM OF INVENTOR IN WAR ON DISEASE
	More than a year ago, Dr. Howard A. Kelly, the noted surgeon of the Johns Hopkins Hospital of Baltimore, asserted that the X-ray apparatus would probably supplant radium in the treatment of certain diseases. At that time, Dr. Kelly had achieved, through the agency of radium, 
	cures that the scalpel could not effect, but despite his enthusiasm, that eminent specialist freely proclaimed greater possibilities for the Roentgen tube when perfected.
	About the same time, Dr. Kelly explained to a Congressional committee just how radium probably wrought its marvelous cures. He said: "Radium goes further than surgery, as surgery only treats that which is visible, and the surgeon is under the constant impulse and desire to save 
	the face of the patient. He does not want to mutilate the patient, and so he thinks that taking out just so much will do. He fails, and there is a recurrence. But the radium, like the blessed light from heaven above, bathes the part, throws its gamma rays, which are its active rays, 
	into the part, acting on all the myriad microscopic cells, not only the manifest, gross, surgical lesions but all those little cells through the surrounding tissues, and it acts like millions of microscopic knives to destroy them, or like a lash to drive them back. In other words, 
	radium will not only do what surgery does, but it goes beyond and takes a class of cases which are utterly beyond surgery."
	But the manipulation or control of this radioactive substance has well-defined limits, and for certain internal applications, this curative medium has not been successfully employed for that reason. As Dr. Kelly expressed it, an X-ray tube susceptible of nice control 
	would make it possible to deal with abdominal cancer, cover a larger area needing this method of attack, and, at the same time, afford cheaper treatment for the suffering multitude. Until recently, though, the X-ray was something of a double-edged weapon in the assault upon disease: 
	the patient was likely to be burned while undergoing exposure to the penetrating rays, and the operator, to safeguard himself, had to stand behind a metal screen and watch his subject from afar through a lead-glass panel.
	When "burns" are spoken of in connection with the X-ray, they should not be confused with superficial burns due to excessive heat. The X-ray burn manifests itself slowly and sometimes only after many days, because the injury is fairly deep-seated; the tissues are destroyed by the chemical 
	effects of the piercing rays, and the patient does not feel the hurt instantly as he would if subjected to a painfully hot body. Indeed, these actinic burns are apt to be malignant in their character and very stubborn in their persistence.
	Now the patient is assured of a New Yorker’s discovery of a burnless X-ray that retains all of the beneficial qualities while being free from harmful ones.
	Charles H. Stanley believes he has evolved a burnless or harmless X-ray, or, to be more exact, produced an apparatus by which he can generate X-rays that will not injure bodily tissues but at the same time will do the corrective work of the gamma rays of radium, described by Dr. Kelly. 
	This invention, he believes, will work therapeutic wonders, and if so, it unquestionably marks one of the big advances of science in its tireless battle with disease. Mr. Stanley is not a physician, but his electrical researches have been inspired alone by a desire to use that agency for the relief of sufferers.
	Fourteen years ago, he began his experiments. He believed cancer could be cured or checked by means of an X-ray tube energized by an alternating current of more than ordinarily high frequency. He managed to obtain unusually high frequencies, but his apparatus lacked the necessary feature of control. 
	From a laboratory point of view, he had something of extreme interest then, indeed so spectacular that it was used later for exhibition purposes, but that was not Mr. Stanley’s goal.
	It is not of present interest to describe how he overcame technical obstacles one after another by tirelessly sticking to a task that would have discouraged most men. Happily, he has the disposition of the born researcher, and what he believed possible he has attained.
    At present, the highest frequencies used therapeutically do not exceed 750 alternations a second. Mr. Stanley has been able to build up these vibrations or waves until they "run into trillions," as the inventor puts it. Indeed, these alternations are of such amazing rapidity that the needle of the meter is apparently 
	at a standstill. In other words, the changing impulses in the circuit follow one another with such velocity that the current is nearly a direct one. How is this accomplished?
    Inasmuch as Mr. Stanley has not yet obtained his patents, he is naturally indisposed to go into details, but he asserts that the results are indisputable. He says he can produce an electric pressure of quite a million volts, and by recourse to a series of transformers, he takes the current delivered from the street mains and, 
	step by step, jumps it up to this limit.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045211/1918-03-13/ed-1/seq-11/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	BIG FIELD FOR WOMEN AS X-RAY WORKERS
	Dr. Mabel Haines Tells of Great Progress Made in Tumoring Disease
	Feminine Efficiency
	Modern Methods Have Reduced Danger and Won Laurels for Pioneers
	There is no area for X-ray maniacs, but there is a great need for X-ray workers, according to Dr. Mabel Summer Haines, chief Roentgenologist at the Woman's Hospital, as well as assistant at the Jefferson Hospital.
	"The idea of danger in women with the X-ray is a mistaken one. There is comparatively little now. For just as bacteriologists work with germ cultures and prepare for the accompanying dangers, so do we in the work with the X-ray," Doctor Haines said.
	In her trim black dress, topped by a crown of golden hair and keen blue eyes, she looked in keeping with this splendid profession. An girlish woman with the responsibility of her position. Upon her skill and the twist of a finger depend the lives and happiness of the patients who come to her for X-ray pictures of their 
	hidden wounds and afflictions. The science has advanced so far in the last ten years that a diagnosis of virtually any disease can be made through X-ray pictures.
    We workers protect ourselves from the powerful effects of the rays by means of lead. In taking an ordinary picture we do not operate the machine from the room, but are separated by a lead wall and look at the patient through leaded glass and speak to him through a tube. In some cases of stomach examination, it is necessary 
	to have the machine in the room, but I protect myself with a lead apron and gloves. In the early days of its discovery, the doctors who used it frequently received burns which resulted in cancers from the continued work with the rays, but that is a thing of the past."
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1919-07-27/ed-1/seq-28/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	X-Ray Reveals Bomb Secrets Without Peril to Investigator
    Radiography's Rapid Development Eliminates Dangers With Which Authorities Long Have Had to Contend in Examining Infernal Machines and Suspicious Packages; Proved an Invaluable Aid in Detecting Camouflaged Contraband During War and Is Rapidly Being Applied to Everyday Uses
	By ROBERT C SERRITT.
	Bombs fashioned by revolutionary Reds and others of their kind will hereafter be robbed of their power to do harm. That is to say, innocent-looking packages and the like, suspected of cloaking infernal machines, are to be promptly radiographed so the authorities can discover their real nature. 
	The police are not going to unpack these instruments of destruction, inviting death or mutilation as a reward for their inquisitiveness. Instead, the searching beams of the X-ray tube are to pierce the “innards” of the bombs and disclose their setup, so they can be rendered harmless without risking lives.
	This precautionary procedure may sound a bit occult, but it simply applies scientific advancement to a relatively new field. Indeed, the wonder is that the Police Department hasn't used this before, given that the development of the X-ray tube has steadily progressed for years, greatly increasing the beams’ penetrative power. 
	Examining infernal machines is actually a minor task compared to the other uses radiography now serves.
	X-rays in War Work
    We had some hints of this protective use of X-rays during the earlier days of the recent war when enemy agents sought to smuggle contraband. One striking example was the discovery of prohibited rubber hidden in bales of cotton destined for Italy. The X-ray revealed the contraband inside the bales without unpacking them. 
	Similarly, during the war, the X-ray was invaluable for detecting camouflaged contraband materials, which could have otherwise passed undetected by human eyes.
    X-rays and Everyday Applications
	The practical use of X-rays has broadened significantly, from inspecting ammunition to identifying flaws in metal products. Even before the war, one cartridge factory employed X-rays to check finished ammunition, ensuring there were no hidden defects. This inspection process has since expanded to other industries, 
	including the examination of steel, shells, and aircraft components. Radiographs reveal internal weaknesses, blow holes, and material inconsistencies that might otherwise lead to accidents or failures.
    Recent advancements also apply to larger structures like reinforced concrete ships, where X-rays can assess whether the metal reinforcement remains correctly placed and check for voids in the concrete. Additionally, radiography has helped in identifying flaws in copper wire and distinguishing different types of steel.
    Finally, X-rays have found applications beyond industry, even in seemingly unrelated fields like pearl fishing, where they are used to inspect oysters for pearls without harming them.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn90061052/1921-03-10/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	HAS ADVANTAGE OVER RADIUM
	Experiments In University Laboratory Make It Possible to Produce X-Rays of More Penetrating Power Than Ever Before
	Cambridge, Mass. — Discoveries made by William Duane, professor of biophysics at Harvard, working in collaboration with research students of physics, have made it possible, according to Harvard physicists, to secure X-rays of more penetrating quality than have ever before been obtained in this country, 
	and these new rays are now to be used for the first time in America for the alleviation of cancer.
	What Discovery Means
	The significance of the discovery was explained in the following statement at Harvard:
	The advantage of X-rays over radium is that the latter is scarce and immensely expensive, costing at present more than $100,000 a gram and can therefore only be used in small quantities. If X-rays were used, it would be possible to make the rays enormously more powerful than has been possible with the limited amount of radium available.
	The trouble with the use of X-rays up to this time has been that they are not as penetrating as the so-called Gamma rays of radium, and the problem of the Harvard physicists has been to secure this needed quality.
	It was known that to secure penetration, it was necessary to secure a high frequency of vibration. The Harvard physicists, after many experiments, found that a physical law known as the quantum law applied to the X-ray spectrum and discovered that they could increase the frequency of the rays and thus their penetration by increasing the voltage of current used in the X-ray tube.
	Gets Enough Voltage
    Professor Duane reports that the tube goes to pieces under a voltage of more than 150,000 volts, but that a sufficiently high voltage has been obtained to make the X-rays very nearly as effective for certain medical purposes as the Gamma rays of radium.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045211/1922-08-22/ed-1/seq-8/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	The uses of the X-ray in medicine have been greatly extended in the last few years. This is largely due to the fact that it has now become almost indispensable in diagnosis. It is used very extensively through various methods to locate foreign bodies in the human system and is of great value in their removal.
	A more recent but fully as important development of the uses of the X-ray is in the diagnosis of chest and gastrointestinal troubles, where its value has been proved to be very great; in fact, a diagnosis of these conditions is rarely made at the present time without X-ray findings. In the latter case, 
	the X-ray is particularly helpful as an aid in discovering ulcers in the gastro-intestinal tract and the presence of tumor formations.
	For treatment purposes, the X-ray is being shown each year to have a greater and greater value. Originally the machine was used almost exclusively for radiographic purposes (that is for the making of what is commonly known as an 'X-ray picture'), but a little later its therapeutic value was discovered and appreciated.
	These therapeutic benefits have been increasing from year to year, and at the present time, it is used largely for the treatment of various benign and malignant tumors, and it is also of much assistance in the treatment of various skin lesions. The use of the X-ray in the case of tumors tends to shut down the blood supply 
	to some extent by creating arteritis or a thickening of the walls of the vessel supplying the tumor.
	Its value in determining the condition and position of fragments in cases of fracture is without question, and the radiograph is of great assistance in the proper setting of those fragments with relation to each other.
	There have been many recent improvements in the mechanism of the X-ray. One of the most important of these allows the use of a very high voltage, producing a twenty-inch spot-gap. This, with proper precautions, has proved of much use in a therapeutic way, particularly in the case of malignant conditions for deep-seated lesions.
	Most of our own work in the bureau is diagnostic. For this purpose, we use duplexed films, which lessens the exposure required in radiographic work.
	With proper precautions, the danger of burns in the use of the X-ray machine is now so small as to be negligible. Of course, it is necessary that these precautions be taken both with respect to the person being X-rayed and the operator of the apparatus. Sheet lead has been found to be the best preventive of X-ray burns. 
	These burns are inflicted by what are known as the 'soft rays,' and the lead absorbs these rays. Sheet lead is used between the tube and the operator, and has been found to be very effective.
	A person burned by the X-ray is not immediately conscious of the burn. In the course of time, dermatitis begins, and if deep-seated enough, it may develop in the underlying structure, bone, and muscle as in the case of a third-degree burn. But, as I said, there is now not the slightest reason for an X-ray burn with a competent operator.
	Any part of the human body can be safely X-rayed as long as the proper precautions are observed. There is no reason with the modern improvements of the apparatus for any person to entertain any fear of submitting to an X-ray examination.
	Modern medicine could not get along without the X-ray. The war proved what most of the physicians already knew: that it is indispensable in their work. There is not a specialty in medicine today in which the X-ray findings do not play a leading part in diagnosis, and often in treatment. 
	The reading of a radiograph is usually a question of the interpretation of the various densities shown on it. These densities bear a relationship to normal and pathological conditions.
	</text>
      </result>
      

# Ten additional documents from Chronicling America
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1958-02-23/ed-1/seq-97/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	In the short space of eight months, a terrific and, in the main, unwarranted scare has been built up about X-rays. Last June, the findings of the Special Subcommittee on Radiation of the Congressional Committee on Atomic Energy were made public. Shortly after, a report prepared for the National Academy of Sciences was given wide publicity. 
	The report warned that X-rays of the teeth, chest, and other portions of the body could be dangerous because some radiation reached the reproductive organs.
	Beyond any question, a good many of the 100 million people a year who get X-rays have been frightened. Beyond any question, a certain number of them are already refusing X-rays that would be helpful in diagnosing their illnesses.
    As Dr. Edith H. Quimby of the Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons says: 'So much has been written and said recently about the dangers from radiation that confusion has resulted. The effect on an appreciable number of individuals has been to frighten them to the point where they refuse even very desirable and necessary X-ray examinations. 
	They do not know what they are afraid of—they’re just afraid.'
    Dentists report that some patients are flatly rejecting annual X-rays of their teeth. Pennsylvania and other states have recently outlawed the use of X-ray machines in shoe stores. Mothers who want pregnancy X-rays are being turned down by their obstetricians. It is reported that patronage of the National Tuberculosis Association mobile X-ray 
	vans has taken a noticeable drop. A professor of radiobiology at Stanford University’s School of Medicine reports: 'The X-ray scare is worrying a great many people and is causing them to make foolish decisions. One director of student health here at the University has stopped all routine chest surveys.'
	A Philadelphia radiologist reports: 'This whole X-ray scare has really gone to the ridiculous. Just yesterday, a 60-year-old woman adamantly refused a radiological study which she needed. She had been reading about X-ray damage to the reproductive organs causing genetic mutations in succeeding generations and she didn’t want to put her grandchildren, 
	who lived in another city, in danger!'
	One important factor behind the scare is the atmosphere of fear built up by the radiation peril of A-bombs and H-bombs. Another factor behind the rising confusion is the distortions that have taken place when some of the recent scientific findings have been repeated by people who did not entirely understand them.
	The fact is that X-ray machines and fluoroscopes, when not used properly, can damage the reproductive cells. These cells are very sensitive to radiation, and damage to them can cause genetic mutations in future generations. The National Academy of Sciences has recommended a safety limit of no more than ten roentgens (a unit for measuring 
	radiation exposure) of man-made radiation to the reproductive organs from birth to age 30—the main years of child-bearing.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1948-01-25/ed-1/seq-102/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	1,000,000-volt X-rays examine the thickest castings for internal flaws.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1960-10-09/ed-1/seq-139/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	They fear the effects of X-rays. But by avoiding X-rays, they may be missing vitally important medical aid.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn94050960/1955-11-01/ed-1/seq-4/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn95060104/1947-01-25/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1962-11-04/ed-1/seq-281/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	Using x-rays to check cement making. General Electric has developed an automatic chemical analyzer tailored to the needs of the cement industry. An x-ray emission gauge provides instantaneous and continuous flow analysis of cement mixes—a major step toward automatic control of cement making.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88063294/1944-11-05/ed-1/seq-85/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	At present Dr. Kerst’s betatron hurls out these electron bullet streams of 20,000,000 volt energy. They strike a metal target, and there are produced X-rays of 20,000,000 volts, in contrast with the standard 200,000-volt X-rays used in deep cancer treatment.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042461/1896-12-06/ed-1/seq-17/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	As electricity is a phenomenon familiar to us all, it is not necessary for me to dwell on its more familiar effects, as that, for instance, of heating a conductor, as it does when it passes through the filament of an incandescent lamp; on its effects of attraction and repulsion of currents for each other, 
	as in the case of electric motors; nor of its effects on a magnetic needle, as in our instruments for measuring electricity.
    This leads up to the other forms of ether disturbances, and to molecular motion set up by electricity, which produces luminescence, and we arrive at the next in order, the X or Roentgen rays. A light that penetrates solid bodies, and the discovery of which so surprised us a few months ago. It has been said 
	that an amateur photographer may photograph a person or a skeleton in his own house, "through a flight of stairs and a deal door." I have even heard it suggested that one would have to line his house with lead or glass, which are almost impenetrable to the rays, if one wished to protect himself from the photographic fiend.
    The term, "a new light," is rather confusing; for it is not a light in the sense in which we are in the habit of thinking. The rays which produce this wonderful effect are not very luminous, in fact they may not be luminous at all; yet they produce luminosity, the matter is still in dispute. 
	The English school considers them material electrified particles, proceeding in straight lines; the contending authorities insist that the rays are similar to those of light, transverse undulations in ether. So you see, it is almost the same dispute which proved so vexatious to the ancients.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1925-05-10/ed-1/seq-50/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	X-RAY AS AN AID IN DIAGNOSIS
    This is one of a series of popular health articles furnished by the Medical Society of the District of Columbia.
	The discovery of X-rays is one of the greatest contributions of science to human welfare. The discovery as now used marks a new era in the diagnosis of disease. X-rays were discovered by William Conrad Roentgen 30 years ago. He did not know what they were and chose the algebraic symbol "X" to denote this fact. 
	They are now frequently spoken of as Roentgen rays in honor of their discoverer.
    From the first it was foreshadowed that they might prove of great value in medicine, but, like many other discoveries, it was several years before they became of much practical use. Now they are considered almost indispensable, and their use has been extended to nearly every branch of medical practice.
	X-rays depend for their value upon their ability to register on a photographic film or fluorescent screen the varying densities of the structures through which they pass. They do not depict the organs and tissues of the body as they appear when dissected, but they do portray with amazing clearness their comparative densities. 
	Bones, being much more dense than the surrounding flesh, intercept more of the rays. For this reason, bones are shown more distinctly than any of the other structures of the body. Hence, X-rays are of great value in the diagnosis of diseases and injuries of the skeleton and for the location of foreign substances that have a greater density than the tissues in which they are lodged.
    Shows Diseased Tissue.
	There are also many diseases of the fleshy parts of the entire body which affect density in such a way as to make diseased tissue readily recognizable by X-ray examination. The size, position, and movements of the heart are readily observed, and enlargements of some of the arteries, known as aneurysms, can also be demonstrated. 
	Hardening of the arteries, which has progressed to a stage where deposits of lime in them have occurred, can also be shown.
	The lungs are soft, spongy structures, and when normal are quite translucent to the rays. When they are diseased, however, they are apt to become more or less solidified, and the location, size, and other characteristics of the solidified areas can be seen. The X-rays contribute a great deal to our knowledge of tuberculosis, 
	pneumonia, and other diseases of the lungs, and also of the membrane covering the lungs, which is the part affected in pleurisy.
	</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89053729/1914-01-18/ed-1/seq-28/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	Dr. Robert Knox, director of the Electrical and Radiotherapeutic Department of the Cancer Hospital, has issued a warning against false hopes as a result of the reported radium cures of cancer. He said to an interviewer today:
    "In regard to the value of radium in the treatment of cancer, one must bear in mind that the percentage of cases receiving benefit from this treatment is small. Its action, so far as we know at present, is uncertain.
    "Cases have, or appear to have, been cured by radium when they would probably not have received equal or as much benefit from other methods of treatment so far as we know, but in the interest of the public, it must be definitely pointed out that these cases form a very small percentage of the cases actually treated.
    "Until we know more about its action, one is certainly not justified in describing radium as a specific cure for cancer. I deprecate very strongly the broadcast publicity which is given in this and other countries to the brilliant successes obtained in suitable cases, but which, after all, form only a small percentage of the total. This publicity gives rise to a great 
	amount of false hope in the minds of patients suffering from cancer, and their friends, and unfortunately, they are only too frequently disappointed."
	Value of the X-rays.
	Dr. Knox in a conversation with a representative of The Times emphasized the value of the X-rays in the treatment of cancer. He said he had used the X-rays in cancer cases as well as radium, and in many cases had had equally good results. He believed it very important to carry out researches with the object of producing an X-ray tube which should emit a ray comparable in "hardness" to the radium ray.
    Dr. Knox said he had been hampered in his work by lack of radium, but in any case he would have employed X-rays in cancer treatment along with radium. The value of X-rays even at present, he said, was not fully realized. There was a great future for this treatment. He hoped it would soon be possible to apply X-rays in like fashion to radium. Only the fringe of the ray treatment of cancer had as yet been touched.
	</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>